xsnews.nl 2019-07-07

# Privacy Policy - XS News

We are XS News B.V., acting under the name **XS News**. You can find our contact information at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. XS News is a Usenet Access Provider. We provide our users access to the Usenet on the basis of a subscription (the **Services** ). On our website you can find more information about us and our Services: [www.xsnews.nl](http://www.xsnews.nl/) (the **Website** ). This Privacy Policy applies to the use of our Website and our Services.

In this **Privacy Policy** we explain which personal data we collect through our Website and Services. We also explain for which purposes we use personal data, how we secure them and how long we store them.

We care about your privacy. We comply with the new General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”), which replaced the various privacy laws in European Member States as per 25 May 2018. This legislation will be referred to hereinafter as the “ **Relevant Legislation** ”.

In this Privacy Policy the notion of “ **personal data** ” is understood as all the information by which you can be, directly or indirectly, identified. This definition is in accordance with the Relevant Legislation. Be aware that it is a broad definition: even dynamic IP addresses are considered to be personal data under certain circumstances.

We can collect various sorts of personal data of you when you use our Website and/or Services:

**(Personal) Data** | **Purpose(s)**  
---|---  
First and last name | We use these data to contact you in our correspondence and to enter you in our accounting records in the right manner.  
E-mail address | We use your e-mail address to create an account for you and to be able to contact you. We also use your e-mail address to send you newsletters and direct marketing, unless you object to this. We do not send newsletters and direct marketing to users having a free trial subscription, unless we have permission to do so.  
Phone number | We use your phone number to contact you, if you have left a callback request with us.  
Address data: street and number, postal code, city and country | We use this information for our accounting records and on behalf of the European VAT declarations.  
Bank data: account number, IBAN, BIC | We use these data for the payments of our users having a subscription.  
Credit card data: type of credit card, name card holder, credit card number, security code (cvv) and date of expiry | We use these data for the payments of our users having a subscription.  
Login data: username and password | We use these data to ensure that users can log in with their account.  
User activity log: IP address, login time and URLs visited | We log the activity of users on our Website. We use this information to identify violations of the agreement with the user, such as sharing login data with non-subscribers. The activities regarding the activity on the Usenet are not logged by XS News, but by the processor Abavia.  
  
There are several legal grounds within the Relevant Legislation on the basis of which we are allowed or required to process your personal data:

  * Performance of the agreement: some data are necessary to provide our Services to you as user, such as your name, login data and payment data.

  * Legal obligation: We are required to store several data in our records for Tax Authorities, such as invoice data and your country of residence.

  * Legitimate interest: For other data we have a legitimate interest for processing, such as for logging user activities in order to identify unlawful use of the account.

  * Permission: For sending newsletters and direct marketing through email to users not having a paid subscription we request permission. This permission can also easyily be withdrawn through the unsubscribe link in each newsletter.

We keep the personal data as long as we need them for the purposes stated above:

  * Personal data in our accounting records for Tax Authorities we store for 7 years;

  * All the personal data we use within the context of your account we store as long as you have an account with us and afterwards for a period up to 2 years;

  * Any other data we remove as soon as they are no longer needed for the purposes we collect them for.

We use “ **Processors** ” to assist us in our Services. Within this context these Processors receive personal data from us which they process by our order. We use Processors, for instance, to store the login data and to process the payments of our users.

The Processors we use for the processing of the personal data are:

Processor | Purpose | Location | Explanation  
---|---|---|---  
Abavia | 

Hosting and database

Usenet access

| San Marino | Is established outside the European Union. The services of Abavia are necessary to perform the agreement in order for us to provide our users access to the newsgroups.  
eMerchant Pay | Payment processing | EU and US | Is established in the EU (head-quarters in the UK) and also has a branch in the United States. We only transmit personal data to the offices in the European Union.  
Mailchimp | E-mail marketing | US | Included in the [Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TO6hAAG&status=Active).  
Mollie | Payment processing | EU (NL) | Is established in the EU and thus needs to comply with the Relevant Legislation.  
Multisafepay | Payment processing | EU (NL) | Is established in the EU and thus needs to comply with the Relevant Legislation.  
  
These Processors are required to follow our instructions strictly. Therefore, they will not use the personal data for their own purposes. We will verify that all our Processors comply with the Relevant Legislation.

Apart from the above, we will not share your personal data with others – unless we are legally required to do so.

We may transmit personal data to parties outside the EU, if one of our Processors is established outside the EU. The transmission of data outside the EU will always happen in conformity with the Relevant Legislation (chapter 5 of the GDPR).

We protect all personal data we process from unauthorized and unlawful access, change, disclosure, use and destruction. For instance, we take the following technical and organizational measures to protect the personal data:

  * Security of our network connections through Secure Socket Layer (SSL) and Transport Layer Security (TLS)

  * Encryption of passwords

  * Firewalls

  * VPN secured connection

You can find (hyper)links on our Website which link to the websites of partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors or other third parties. We do not have control of the content or links which appear on these websites and we are not responsible for the practices of websites linked to or from our Website. Furthermore, these websites, including their content and links, may constantly change. These websites may have their own privacy policies, user terms and customer policy. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which are linked to or from our Website, are subject to the terms and conditions and policy of such website.

We use cookies on the Website. A cookie is a simple small text file that can be stored on your computer, when you visit the Website. This text file identifies your browser and/or computer. When you revisit our Website, the cookie ensures, for instance, that our Website recognizes your browser or computer.

We use the following types of cookies:

Functional cookies: Functional cookies are essential to the operation of our Website. They allow you to navigate through our Website and to use the functions incorporated in it.

Analytical or statistical cookies: Analytical cookies are used to check the quality and effectiveness of the Website. For instance, we can see how many users visit the Website and which pages are visited. We use this information to improve our Website and Services.

Tracking cookies: Tracking-cookies follow the click and surf behavior of our visitors. By means of these cookies we can see whether and when you look at your profile and whether you click through to our Website. We may use these cookies to show you ads based on your interests.

If you do not want cookies to be sent to your computer, you can change this in the cookie settings of your browser. Please note that some of the functions or services of our Website may not operate, or not so well, without cookies.

We aim to constantly improve our Website and Services. That is why from time to time we can update this Privacy Policy. If we change our Privacy Policy significantly, then we will state so on our Website together with the revised Privacy Policy.

As laid down in the Relevant Legislation, you have the right to:

  * Ask us for access to and/or copy of the personal data we process of you, including the location where your data are processed, who receives your personal data, how long we keep your data and for what purposes we process the data. We can also transmit such copy to another data controller at your request;

  * Ask us to rectify, review or remove your personal data from our systems;

  * Object to the processing of your personal data;

  * File a complaint with the Dutch Data Protection Authority, if you believe that we process your personal data unlawfully.

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding the manner in which we handle your personal data, please contact us through the contact data below:

**XS NEWS B.V.,**

**acting under the name XS News  
**

New Yorkstraat 10-16  
1175RD Lijnden  
Netherlands

No. Chamber of Trade and Industry: 08145640

VAT number: NL8158.36.946.B01

Telephone: +31 20 820 30 21

E-mail: [support@xsnews.nl](mailto:support@xsnews.nl)
